Kyle Langford

Web Design and Developement

HELLO!

With 10 years experience, I possess a strong blend of design talent and development experience that can be applied to a variety of digital projects. I am passionate about great experiences and helping people utilize technology. I excel at problem-solving and visualizing client needs. I work well managing expectations, communicating ideas and developing strategies for teammates and clients.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Sr. Interactive Designer and Developer — Brunello, Inc.

March 2012 - Current, Boston MA

Experience Designer and Frontend Developer for a small agency specializing in Drupal development and digital design. I am involved with all aspects of web projects including planning, strategy, design, development and quality control. Past clients include Linkwell Health, Enel X, NPQ, Mens Health (Rodale), Sasaki Associates, Dartmouth Alumni Magazine, Princeton Alumni Magazine.

Partner — Raskyl Collective, Ilc.

June 2011 - Current, Boston MA

Contracting and consulting duo for web-based projects ranging from site design, email marketing, and Drupal/Wordpress development. Past clients include GasBuddy, Drizly, Blueshift, RateGravity, Ochard Skateshop, Harvard Developmental Genome Project, Northeastern University (WebGuru.com), Massachusetts and New Hampshire Emergency Nurses Association.

Lead Web Designer — Questex Media, Ilc.

Nov 2010 - March 2012, Newton MA

Interface Designer and Drupal site-building for internal publishing sites. I Led our design team and collaborated with the project manager on meeting business initiatives and goals. Sites used Drupal and covered a wide range of B2B industries.

Digital Producer — Northeastern University, Edtech Center

January 2009 - May 2010, Boston MA

Instructed faculty members and graduate students on software and hardware solutions for their interactive media projects. Formated web-content and worked as part of the University's Second-life presence.

Environmental Designer — Wojciechowski Design

July 2008 - April 2009, Somerville MA

Worked as a project designer creating designs and production proofs for wayfinding solutions for libraries, museums, and schools. Primarily focused on designing an interior and exterior sign-system for the Cambridge Public Library. Produced 3D models in SketchUp which were used to create virtual walkthroughs.

203-803-6120 kyle.langford@gmail.com kylelangford.com Boston, MA

EDUCATION

Northeastern University Boston, MA

Bachelor of Science Dual Major in Graphic Design and Multimedia, Minor in Computer Animation.

COMPETENCIES

Interface Design
Information Architecture
Experience Design
Email Design and Development
Drupal CMS
Frontend Development

TECHNOLOGY

HTML, CSS
JavaScript, jQuery
Node.js
Gulp.js
Git
AngularJS, Angular
Linux
Apache
PHP
MySQL

INTERESTS

Accessibility
Design Systems
Prototyping
Product Design
Application Development